<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security :: Tag :: Black_JJW&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/tags/security/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blackjjw.github.io/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6. Login</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/login/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/login/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, I’ll explain how I made the login function. This project is designed as a single-user program. In other words, only the administrator is authorized to access and operate the system. Therefore, I created a single account with the ID: “admin”.&#xA;1. The design of the login function 1.1 Diagram This shows the communication between the frontend, backend, and DB.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8. Login Log</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/loginlog/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/loginlog/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, I’ll explain how I implemented the login log functionality. Since this is a single-user application, logging each login might seem unnecessary at first. However, I decided to build this feature to enhance security and maintain visibility over all login activities. Recording login attempts allows me to track unauthorized access or unexpected behavior in the system.&#xA;1. The design of the login log function 1.1 Diagram The diagram below illustrates the communication flow between the frontend, backend, and Database during a login process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11. Managing API Keys - Frontend Implementation</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/mngapikeys2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/mngapikeys2/index.html</guid>
      <description>This post outlines the frontend design and implementation for API key management.&#xA;1. The design of the API Key Management 1.1 API Key Management Structure To visualize the layout, I sketched a simple diagram of the API Key management page.&#xA;Left-side Menu Items: Under Settings, several submenus are available.&#xA;Exchanges: Area for managing exchanges.&#xA;API Keys: Area for managing API keys.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18. Securing API keys and secrets with Pydantic settings &#43; .env</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/securingapikeyandsecrets/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/securingapikeyandsecrets/index.html</guid>
      <description>Secrets are easy to leak when the project grows. In this backend, I keep configuration and credentials centralized in a Pydantic Settings class and load them from .env. API keys are encrypted at rest, and JWT secrets never live in code.&#xA;This post documents the exact pattern used in this repo.&#xA;1. Centralized config with Pydantic settings All secrets are defined once in Settings and imported through a single settings instance:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>