<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asyncio :: Tag :: Black_JJW&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/tags/asyncio/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blackjjw.github.io/tags/asyncio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2. Setting Up the Backend</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/startbackend/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/startbackend/index.html</guid>
      <description>1. Installing FastAPI We will use FastAPI as the backend server framework due to its performance and asynchronous capabilities - it’s a better fit than the Flask for real-time and modular systems. Install it along with the ASGI server uvicorn using uv:&#xA;uv pip install &#34;fastapi[all]&#34; uvicorn fastapi[all] : Installs optional dependencies such as: pydantic, httpx, python-multipart, jinja2, email-validator uvicorn : Lightweight ASGI server used to run FastAPI applications 2. Setting the Lifespan in FastAPI To manage startup and shutdown tasks (e.g., initializing connections, cleaning resources), FastAPI provides a lifespan context manager.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12. Refactoring 2: Backend - Applying Async Database Management</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/refactor2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/refactor2/index.html</guid>
      <description>This refactoring adopts asynchronous database management to avoid blocking caused by synchronous I/O.&#xA;Previously, database access was implemented synchronously across services and endpoints, which could block under concurrent workloads. Because this program needs to perform multiple tasks simultaneously, I decided to switch to an async-first approach for database operations.&#xA;1. Config To enable asynchronous PostgreSQL support, install asyncpg:&#xA;uv pip install asyncpg In config.py, I added the following property to build the async SQLAlchemy URL for PostgreSQL:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>