<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postgresql :: Tag :: Black_JJW&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/tags/postgresql/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blackjjw.github.io/tags/postgresql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Project Initialization</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/initializeproject/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/initializeproject/index.html</guid>
      <description>In fact, I had been working on a similar project for some time. Although I tried to complete it, I eventually gave up because it was too complex and inefficient to move forward with. So I decided to restart the project from scratch.&#xA;1. Project Tech Stack Area Tech Backend Python(FastAPI), Redis, Redis Queue(RQ), PostgreSQL Frontend React + Vite Infra Docker, Docker Compose, .env, .yml 2. Backend Settings 2.1 backend.DockerFile This DockerFile installs backend system dependencies and Python packaging tool(uv) for the Python 3.12.11 environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4. Set Configurations</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/setconfig/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/setconfig/index.html</guid>
      <description>I used a .env file to store configuration values. To load them into the application, I’m using BaseSettings from the pydantic_settings package.&#xA;Here’s an sample .env file used to configure the PostgreSQL database connection:&#xA;POSTGRES_HOST=localhost POSTGRES_PORT=5432 POSTGRES_USER=myuser POSTGRES_PASSWORD=secret POSTGRES_DB=cryptobot 1. Settings pydantic_settings.BaseSettings is an extended version of Pydantic’s model designed for managing environment variables.&#xA;It’s commonly used in Python backend frameworks like FastAPI to load and validate environment variables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8. Login Log</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/loginlog/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/loginlog/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, I’ll explain how I implemented the login log functionality. Since this is a single-user application, logging each login might seem unnecessary at first. However, I decided to build this feature to enhance security and maintain visibility over all login activities. Recording login attempts allows me to track unauthorized access or unexpected behavior in the system.&#xA;1. The design of the login log function 1.1 Diagram The diagram below illustrates the communication flow between the frontend, backend, and Database during a login process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10. Managing API Keys - Backend Implementation</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/mngapikeys1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/mngapikeys1/index.html</guid>
      <description>Managing API Keys from multiple exchanges requires both exchange metadata management and secure key storage. In this post, I describe the database schema and service logic used to support this.&#xA;1. The Design of the API Key Management System 1.1 ERD The functionality is based on three relational tables: TB_USER, TB_EXCHANGES, and TB_EXCHANGE_API_KEYS.&#xA;TB_EXCHANGES stores registered exchanges.&#xA;exchange_id: Unique exchange identifier exchange_name: Name of the exchange TB_EXCHANGE_API_KEYS manages the API keys linked to exchanges per user.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>