<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multi Crypto Trading Tool :: Black_JJW&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/index.html</link>
    <description>Project Overview This project is designed to aggregate real-time data from multiple cryptocurrency exchanges and execute automated trades using a variety of strategies. Performance and scalability are key priorities in its development.&#xA;📊 System Architecture To better illustrate the architecture of this project, the diagram below shows how different components interact within a Docker Compose environment:&#xA;All services communicate over a shared Docker network. The Core Layer includes the frontend, backend, and worker services. The Infra Layer consists of Redis (for both queuing and caching). The Monitoring Layer captures metrics using Prometheus and displays dashboards via Grafana. 📁 Dev Logs 1. Project Initialization 2. Start Backend 3. Logger Configuration 4. Set Configuration 5. Database Connection Manager 6. Login Page Setup 7. Topbar Menu 8. Login Log 9. Refactoring 1: Backend - Separate AuthService and Move Login API 10. Managing API Keys - Backend Implementation 11. Managing API Keys - Frontend Implementation 12. Refactoring 2: Backend - Applying Async Database Management 13. Login Log - Frontend 14. Makefile Setup 15. FastAPI Service Architecture: Thin Routers, Service Layer, and DTO Patterns 16. Idempotency and Replay Safety for Trade Execution Endpoints 17. Testing Async Services in FastAPI: pytest‑asyncio Fixtures and Mocks 18. Securing API keys and secrets with Pydantic settings + .env 19. Observability for trading systems: logging, metrics, and tracing basics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dev Logs</title>
      <link>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blackjjw.github.io/multi-crypto-trading-tool/dev-logs/index.html</guid>
      <description>This section contains various development logs:&#xA;1. Project Initialization 2. Start Backend 3. Logger Configuration 4. Set Configuration 5. Database Connection Manager 6. Login Page Setup 7. Topbar Menu 8. Login Log 9. Refactoring 1: Backend - Separate AuthService and Move Login API 10. Managing API Keys - Backend Implementation 11. Managing API Keys - Frontend Implementation 12. Refactoring 2: Backend - Applying Async Database Management 13. Login Log - Frontend 14. Makefile Setup 15. FastAPI Service Architecture: Thin Routers, Service Layer, and DTO Patterns 16. Idempotency and Replay Safety for Trade Execution Endpoints 17. Testing Async Services in FastAPI: pytest‑asyncio Fixtures and Mocks 18. Securing API keys and secrets with Pydantic settings + .env 19. Observability for trading systems: logging, metrics, and tracing basics</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>